JULIETTE KERNION

j@kernion.me 512-451-6929 8313 Franwood Lane Austin, TX 78757

I excel at writing and editing product documentation, online tutorials, and technical blog posts for targeted audiences. I collaborate effectively with subject-matter experts and other writers to produce clear, engaging content. I'm an experienced and efficient documentation project manager and team lead.

STRENGTHS

Strong project management and leadership skills: Led communication project teams, scoped documentation requests (Jira), created communication plans, and coordinated with subject-matter experts and stakeholders. Mentored team members. Experienced in product development methodologies, including Agile and Kanban.

Content development for a wide range of audiences: Created resources for software developers, technical integration teams, non-technical business professionals, nonprofit volunteers, and online shoppers.

Content and source management tool knowledge: Skilled in MadCap Flare, Confluence, and Oxygen (XML, DITA), and in content management systems (CMS) such as WordPress, Jekyll, Drupal, and Medium. Experienced editor in Markdown, HTML, and XML. Proficiency in GitHub, SVN, and Perforce.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Content Architect

Indeed

2017-Present

- Increase internal transparency by managing Engineering Chief of Staff and related team communications, such as blog posts, email newsletters, and wiki pages.
- Promote Indeed Engineering accomplishments outside the company by writing and editing public blog posts. Write social media posts to boost blog traffic. Manage localization of blog posts into Japanese.
- Improve communications overall by developing content as needed, including open source tool
 documentation on company GitHub repos, internal technical procedures and tutorials, and engineer
 onboarding materials.
- Amplify company profile by assisting Engineering staff with conference proposals and presentations.
- Encourage Indeed employees to share their knowledge with colleagues by developing introductory writing training resources.

Staff and Senior Technical Writer

Bazaarvoice

2012-2017

- Improved users' understanding of the company's flagship product, Conversations, by leading a major knowledge base re-architecture, redesign, and source migration to GitHub.
- Built and updated online product documentation for internal and external users, including business professionals, client developers (for SDKs), and internal support staff.
- Strengthened and unified the Product Knowledge team in tandem with management by mentoring new team members, providing peer feedback, and improving editorial processes.

Senior Technical Writer

Convio

2009-2011

- Improved client user experience for mid-market donor management product for nonprofits, both by expanding and restructuring online resources and by improving user interface text and inline context help.
- Received a peer-nominated Exceptional Performance Award.

JULIETTE KERNION

EXPERIENCE (continued)

Technical Writer/Editor IV

The University of Texas at Austin

2007-2009

As part of Information Technology Services (ITS) Strategic Communications team, managed communications projects. Wrote and edited help topics and news articles for external and internal ITS websites and the Vice President for Information Technology office.

Technical Writer Pointserve 2006-2007

Improved end-user help, technical reference materials, and marketing materials for enterprise product suite.

Technical Writer National Instruments 2000-2005

Wrote and edited software manuals, online help, and web-based support documents using single-sourcing methods, including XML.

PUBLICATIONS AND PROJECTS

Civic and company hackathon teams:

- ATX Hack for Change 2014: Led team of writers to create City of Austin Open Data Portal How-To Wiki in conjunction with Open Austin
- Bazaarvoice BV IO 2014: Led all-writer team to create SEO Developer Resources wizard, which won Closest to Reality award
- BV 2016 Hackathon: Member of writer team to scope Knowledge Base Redesign project, which won In the Know award

Editor and founder of Slackerwood (slackerwood.com), a news website about Austin film, from 2006-2015. Assigned, wrote, scheduled, fact-checked, and edited articles and features. Managed a team of seven regular contributors plus guest writers/photographers. Awarded Best Austin Movie Blog (Critics Picks) by *Austin Chronicle* in 2011.

Published in: Indiewire, *SXSWorld* magazine, Crooked Marquee, Hammer to Nail, Cinematical/Moviefone, Movies.com, The Circuit (*Variety* film-festival blog), anthology *Do You Know What It Means to Miss New Orleans* (Chin Music Press, 2006), *The Onion* (Austin edition).

EDUCATION

James A. Michener Post-Graduate Fellowship

The University of Texas Center for Writers

Master of Arts, Radio-Television-Film

The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Arts cum laude, News-Editorial Journalism

Minors in political science and history Louisiana State University, Baton Rouge